Finding Aid for the Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Clippings, 1960-1997, IX.; Folders 286-489
  - January 23, 1973 Guardian (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 328)
  - April 21, 1973 Buffalo Evening News, Also filed under interviews by John Dwyer. (Box 12, Folder 329)
  - December 24, 1973 Newsweek (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 12, Folder 330)
  - December 1974 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 331)
  - March 20, 1975 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 12, Folder 332)
  - April 1975 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 333)
  - June 12, 1975 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 334)
  - November 26, 1975 Le Monde (Paris, France) (Box 12, Folder 335)
  - 1975 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 336)
  - 1975 Courier Express (Buffalo, NY) (Box 12, Folder 337)
  - April 28, 1976 Courier Express (Buffalo, NY) (Box 12, Folder 338)
  - June 2, 1976 Buffalo Evening News, June in Buffalo review. (Box 12, Folder 339)
  - June 5, 1976 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 340)
  - June 5, 1976 Courier Express (Buffalo, NY) (Box 12, Folder 341)
  - August 28, 1976 Il Gazzettino (Venice, Italy) (Box 12, Folder 342)
  - August 28, 1976 L'unita (Rome, Italy), Could be Milan edition. (Box 12, Folder 343)
  - September 3, 1976 Rinascita? (Box 12, Folder 344)
  - September 11, 1976 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 345)
  - September 26, 1976 The Observer (London, England) (Box 12, Folder 346)
  - October 11, 1976 Los Angeles Times (Box 12, Folder 347)
  - October 31, 1976 Corriere della sera (Milan, Italy) (Box 12, Folder 348)
  - October 31, 1976 Il Gazzettino (Venice, Italy) (Box 12, Folder 349)
  - October 31, 1976 L'unita (Rome, Italy) (Box 12, Folder 350)
  - November 27, 1976 Buffalo Evening News (Box 12, Folder 351)
  - 1976, unknown source (Box 12, Folder 352)
  - January 15, 1977 Classical Music (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 353)
  - February 1, 1977 Corriere della sera (Milan, Italy), Il Giornale (Milan or Naples, Italy) L'unita (Rome, Italy) (Box 13, Folder 354)
  - March 1977 Hi-Fi News & Record Review (Croydon, England) (Box 13, Folder 355)
  - May 29, 1977 Courier Express (Buffalo, NY), June in Buffalo review. (Box 13, Folder 356)
  - May 1977 Music and Musicians (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 357)
  - June 9, 1977 Corriere della sera (Milan, Italy) (Box 13, Folder 358)
  - June 9, 1977 La republica (Italian) (Box 13, Folder 359)
  - June 9, 1977 L'unita (Rome, Italy) (Box 13, Folder 360)
  - June 12, 1977 Corriere della sera (Venice, Italy) (Box 13, Folder 361)
  - June 12, 1977 Paese sera? (Box 13, Folder 362)
  - June 14, 1977 International Herald Tribune (Box 13, Folder 363)
  - June 26, 1977 Sunday Telegraph (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 364)
  - August 2, 1977 Financial Times (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 365)
  - August 25, 1977 Financial Times (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 366)
  - October 1977 Buffalo Evening News (Box 13, Folder 367)
  - May 26, 1978 Saarbrücker Zeitung (Box 13, Folder 368)
  - September 10, 1978 Courier Express (Box 13, Folder 369)
  - October 21, 1978 Der Tagespiegel? (Box 13, Folder 370)
  - October 23, 1978 Die Welt (Berlin, Germany) (Box 13, Folder 371)
  - November 23, 1978 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 372)
  - December 11, 1978 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 13, Folder 373)
  - February 1979 High Fidelity/Musical America (Box 13, Folder 374)
  - September 1979 Scena (Berlin(?), Germany) (Box 13, Folder 375)
  - October 1979 Music and Letters (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 376)
  - November 1979 Buffalo Evening News (Box 13, Folder 377)
  - March 1980 High Fidelity/Musical America (Box 13, Folder 378)
  - April 14, 1980 Chicago Tribune (Box 13, Folder 379)
  - April 15, 1980 Chicago Sun-Times (Box 13, Folder 380)
  - June 16, 1980 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 13, Folder 381)
  - June 29, 1980 Buffalo Evening News (Box 13, Folder 382)
  - June 1980 Notes (Canton, MA) (Box 13, Folder 383)
  - July 27, 1980 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 384)
  - January 21, 1981 Los Angeles Herald Examiner (Box 13, Folder 385)
  - January 22, 1981 Los Angeles Times (Box 13, Folder 386)
  - March 8, 1981, from unknown source (Box 13, Folder 387)
  - May 21, 1981 Le Monde (Paris, France) (Box 13, Folder 388)
  - October 6, 1981 The Guardian (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 389)
  - November 9, 1981 St. Galler Tagblatt (Box 13, Folder 390)
  - 1981? Buffalo Evening News (Box 13, Folder 391)
  - March 13, 1982 Buffalo Evening News (Box 13, Folder 392)
  - March 22, 1982 San Francisco Chronicle (Box 13, Folder 393)
  - March 29, 1982 Daily Telegraph (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 394)
  - March 29, 1982 The Guardian (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 395)
  - March 29, 1982, From an unknown source (Box 13, Folder 396)
  - March 30, 1982 Financial Times (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 397)
  - March 30, 1982 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 13, Folder 398)
  - April 2, 1982 Sunday Times (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 399)
  - April 25, 1982 Sunday Dispatch (Moline, IL) (Box 13, Folder 400)
  - May 9, 1982 Sunday Dispatch(Moline, IL) (Box 13, Folder 401)
  - March 9, 1983 New York Times, two different editions (Box 13, Folder 402)
  - March 12-13, 1983 St. Louis Globe Democrat (Box 13, Folder 403)
  - June 5, 1983 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 404)
  - October 4, 1983 Kultur (Bonn, Germany) (Box 13, Folder 405)
  - December 6, 1983 Toronto Star (Box 13, Folder 406)
  - April 4, 1984 Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (Box 13, Folder 407)
  - June 24, 1984 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 408)
  - September 30, 1984 Buffalo Evening News (Box 13, Folder 409)
  - November 1, 1984 The Listener (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 410)
  - November 15, 1984 The Listener (London, England) (Box 13, Folder 411)
  - January 21, 1985 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 412)
  - April 7, 1985 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 413)
  - April 17, 1985 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 414)
  - June 30, 1985 Der Tagespiegel (Box 13, Folder 415)
  - July 5, 1985 De Volkskrant (Amsterdam, Netherlands), With English translation (Box 13, Folder 416)
  - February 17, 1986 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 417)
  - February 24, 1986 Los Angeles Times (Box 13, Folder 418)
  - April 9, 1986 Los Angeles Herald Examiner (Box 13, Folder 419)
  - May 7, 1986 San Francisco Chronicle (Box 13, Folder 420)
  - May 16, 1986 Ventura County (CA) Star Free Press (Box 13, Folder 421)
  - July 8, 1986 NRC Handelsblad (Rotterdam, Netherlands) (Box 13, Folder 422)
  - July 25, 1986 Darmstädter Echo (Box 13, Folder 423)
  - July 25, 1986 Darmstädter Tagblatt (Box 13, Folder 424)
  - November 12, 1986 San Francisco Chronicle (Box 13, Folder 425)
  - November 12, 1986 San Francisco Examiner (Box 13, Folder 426)
  - December 21, 1986 New York Times (Box 13, Folder 427)
  - January 17, 1987 Rheinischer (Box 14, Folder 428)
  - January 17, 1987 Weltdeutsche (Box 14, Folder 429)
  - February 14, 1987 Frankfurter Rundschau (Box 14, Folder 430)
  - April 16, 1987 River Falls Journal (River Falls, WI) (Box 14, Folder 431)
  - April 28, 1987 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 14, Folder 432)
  - May 21, 1987 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 433)
  - May 1987 Univ. of Wisconsin River Falls Student Voice (Box 14, Folder 434)
  - June 13-16, 1987 Amersfoortse Courant (Amersfoort,Netherlands), Het Parool (Amsterdam, Netherlands), Nwsbl von Noorden (Nieuwsblad van het Noorden (Groningen, Netherlands)), De rergraat, Utrechts Nieuwsblad (Utrecht, Netherlands), De Volkskrant (Amsterdam, Netherlands) (Box 14, Folder 435)
  - September 4, 1987 Buffalo Evening News, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 436)
  - September 4, 1987 Financial Times (London, England), Obituary (Box 14, Folder 437)
  - September 4, 1987 Independent London, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 438)
  - September 4, 1987 New York Times, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 439)
  - September 4, 1987 Newsday, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 440)
  - September 5, 1987 London Times, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 441)
  - September 5, 1987 London Times (Box 14, Folder 442)
  - September 5, 1987 Obituaries from 4 Japanese newspapers: Asahi News, Tokyo, Mainichi, Yomiuri (Box 14, Folder 443)
  - September 5-6, 1987 Süddeutsche Zeitung (Munich, Germany) (Box 14, Folder 444)
  - September 5-7, 1987 Kurier (Berlin, Germany)(September 7); Presse (Vienna, Austria) (September 5-6) (Box 14, Folder 445)
  - September 7, 1987 Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 446)
  - September 7, 1987 Frankfurter Rundschein, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 447)
  - September 7, 1987 Globe and Mail (Toronto, Ont.), Obituary (Box 14, Folder 448)
  - September 11, 1987 Daily Telegraph, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 449)
  - September 14, 1987 Time Magazine, Obituary (Box 14, Folder 450)
  - October 4, 1987 Buffalo Evening News, A tribute written by Yvar Mikhashoff. (Box 14, Folder 451)
  - October 5, 1987 Performing Arts Journal, In Japanese (Box 14, Folder 452)
  - October 6, 1987 Village Voice (New York, NY), Obituary (Box 14, Folder 453)
  - November 1987 Ongaku-Geijutsu, Tribute by Jo Kondo (Box 14, Folder 454)
  - December 1987 Neue Zeitschrift für Musik (Mainz, Germany), Obituary (Box 14, Folder 455)
  - February 13, 1988 Financial Times (London) (Box 14, Folder 456)
  - February 13, 1988 Telegraph (London) (Box 14, Folder 457)
  - February 13, 1988, from unknown source (Box 14, Folder 458)
  - February 18, 1988 The Times (London), Review by P.G. (Box 14, Folder 459)
  - February 18, 1988 The Times (London), Review by Robert Maycock. (Box 14, Folder 460)
  - March 1988 Newsday (Hempstead, NY) (Box 14, Folder 461)
  - April 19, 1988 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 14, Folder 462)
  - July 30, 1989 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 463)
  - April 1, 1990 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 464)
  - November 5, 1990 Frankfurter Rundschau (Box 14, Folder 465)
  - January 12, 1991 De Volkskrant (Amsterdam, Netherlands), With English translation. (Box 14, Folder 466)
  - January 14, 1991 NRC (Nieuwe Rotterdamse Courant)(Rotterdam, Netherlands), With English translation. (Box 14, Folder 467)
  - January 14, 1991 Trouw (Amsterdam, Netherlands), With English translation. (Box 14, Folder 468)
  - January 14, 1991 De Volkskrant (Amsterdam, Netherlands), With English translation. (Box 14, Folder 469)
  - January 16, 1991 Financial Times (London, England) (Box 14, Folder 470)
  - January 19, 1991 The Independent (London, England) (Box 14, Folder 471)
  - July 30, 1991 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 14, Folder 472)
  - January 12, 1992 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 473)
  - October 15, 1993 Buffalo Evening News (Box 14, Folder 474)
  - March 1, 1994 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 475)
  - March 1994 Tempo (London, England) (Box 14, Folder 476)
  - June 28, 1994 Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (Box 14, Folder 477)
  - November 5-6, 1994 Der Standard ? (Box 14, Folder 478)
  - November 8, 1994 Die Presse (Vienna, Austria) (Box 14, Folder 479)
  - November 10, 1994 Die Presse (Vienna, Austria) (Box 14, Folder 480)
  - November 10, 1994 Wiener Zeitung (Vienna, Austria) (Box 14, Folder 481)
  - November 24, 1994 Der Standard? (Box 14, Folder 482)
  - December 8, 1994 Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (Box 14, Folder 483)
  - April 29, 1996 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 484)
  - July 23, 1996 Village Voice (New York, NY) (Box 14, Folder 485)
  - July 31, 1996 Buffalo Evening News (Box 14, Folder 486)
  - August 6, 1996 New York Times (Box 14, Folder 487)
  - April 2-8, 1997 Art Voice (Buffalo) (Box 14, Folder 488)
  - no date Miscellaneous clippings, 1 folder (37 clippings) (Box 14, Folder 489)
- Photographs, 1939-1987, X.; 1 container (54 photographs)
  The collection of fifty-four photographs includes candid snapshots and more formal portraits. Others in the photographs include Barbara Monk Feldman, Nils Vigeland, Eberhard Blum, the members of the Kronos Quartet, and John Adams. More than a dozen of the shots were taken by Rolf Hanns at Darmstadt in 1986. Eight of the photographs (47-54) were printed from negatives received with the collection. An additional two portraits by Rolf Hanns and five photographs of scenes from the first performance of Feldman's Neither in June 1977 in Rome are housed in the Oversize Box at the end of the collection.
  The photographs have been roughly organized by size and then chronologically
  - Morton Feldman at piano, 1963, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 01)
  - Morton Feldman in Rome with Accademia di Francia (Villa Medici) in background, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 02)
  - Morton Feldman in Rome with Accademia di Francia (Villa Medici) in background, 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 03)
  - Morton Feldman in bus window, with photographer seen in reflection, Palermo, December 1968, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 04)
  - Morton Feldman examining score, Cologne, 1978, 1 photograph; Masotti, Roberto, 1947- (Box 15, Item 05)
  - Morton Feldman at piano, with baby, 1978, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 06)
  - Morton Feldman with Kronos Quartet, undated, 1 photograph; Newson, George (Box 15, Item 07)
  - Morton Feldman with Kronos Quartet, undated, 1 photograph; Newson, George (Box 15, Item 08)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, 1984-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 09)
  - Morton Feldman seated at lectern, Festival Nieuwe Muziek, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 10)
  - Morton Feldman seated at lectern, Festival Nieuwe Muziek, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 11)
  - Morton Feldman seated at lectern, Festival Nieuwe Muziek, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 12)
  - Morton Feldman seated at lectern, Festival Nieuwe Muziek, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 13)
  - Morton Feldman seated at lectern, Festival Nieuwe Muziek, undated, 1 photograph; Marcus, Bunita (Box 15, Item 14)
  - Morton Feldman seated at lectern, Festival Nieuwe Muziek, undated, 1 photograph; Marcus, Bunita (Box 15, Item 15)
  - Morton Feldman at piano, 1978, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 16)
  - Morton Feldman with binoculars, on Long Island, 1980, 1 photograph; Marcus, Bunita (Box 15, Item 17)
  - Morton Feldman with Barbara Monk at table, 1986, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 18)
  - Morton Feldman with Barbara Monk and friends, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 19)
  - Morton Feldman with Francesco Clemente, and John Lurie, 1986, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 20)
  - Morton Feldman portrait in hat, profile, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 21)
  - Morton Feldman in audience at Darmstadt, 1986, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 22)
  - Morton Feldman with Barbara Monk Feldman, on their wedding day, 1987-06, 1 photograph; Marcus, Bunita (Box 15, Item 23)
  - Morton Feldman at piano, Galleria Nazionale dell'Umbria, Sala Maggiore, Perugia, Italy, 1974-02-24, 1 photograph; Williams, Jan (Box 15, Item 24)
  - Morton Feldman at unidentified function, circa 1960, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 25)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, 1984-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 26)
  - Morton Feldman in audience at Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 27)
  - Morton Feldman with Nils Vigeland and Eberhard Blum, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 28)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and Nils Vigeland, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 29)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and Nils Vigeland, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 30)
  - Nils Vigeland and Eberhard Blum; Feldman in audience, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 31)
  - Morton Feldman, Nils Vigeland, and Eberhard Blum in group hug, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 32)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 33)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 34)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 35)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 36)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 37)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 38)
  - Morton Feldman in conversation, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 39)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 40)
  - Morton Feldman In conversation at table, Darmstadt, 1986-07, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 41)
  - Morton Feldman with John Adams and Frans van Rossum, Dean of the CalArts Music School, 1987-01-10, 1 photograph; Freeman, Betty (Box 15, Item 42)
  - Morton Feldman with John Adams, 1987-01-10, 1 photograph; Freeman, Betty (Box 15, Item 43)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, 1987-01, 1 photograph; Freeman, Betty (Box 15, Item 44)
  - Exhibit display of scores by Earle Brown, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 45)
  - Photographic print of first page of Feldman's The Swallows of Salangan, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 46)
  - Morton Feldman at the Perisphere, New York World's Fair, 1939 or 1940, 1939, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 47)
  - Morton Feldman with John Cage, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 48)
  - Morton Feldman portrait with music score of Neither in background (also used with superimposed image of Samuel Beckett), undated, 1 photograph; Enser, Dennis (Box 15, Item 49)
  - Morton Feldman with unidentified people at gathering, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 50)
  - Morton Feldman with Barbara Monk Feldman in foreground, undated, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 15, Item 51)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, 1984, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 52)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, 1984, 1 photograph; Hanns, Rolf (Box 15, Item 53)
  - Morton Feldman portrait, with cigarette, 1978, 1 photograph; Masotti, Roberto, 1947- (Box 15, Item 54)
- Oversize, circa 1955-1994, XI.; 1 box
  Includes oversized photographs, an award from the American Music Center, 1 poster from a memorial concert held 1994 at the University at Buffalo, a negative photocopy of an unidentified leaf of manuscript in French addressed to "Cher John", and an unframed tempera on paper by Rolf Hanns, titled Ultramarinblau. Also included is a box of twenty-two 35 mm slides, chiefly of pages from Feldman's scores.
  In order as received.
  - Poster for Feldman memorial concerts at the State University of New York at Buffalo, March 15-16, 1994 (Box 16, Item 1)
  - Letter of distinction awarded to Morton Feldman by the American Music Center, 1987 (Box 16, Item 2)
  - Negative photocopy of unidentified manuscript leaf, in French, addressed to "Cher John", undated (Box 16, Item 3)
  - Portrait photograph of Morton Feldman by Rolf Hanns, Darmstadt, July 1986 (Box 16, Item 4)
  - Portrait photograph of Morton Feldman seated by Rolf Hanns, Darmstadt, July 1986 (Box 16, Item 5)
  - Photographs of scenes from the premiere performance of the Feldman and Samuel Beckett work, Neither, in Rome, June 1977 (Box 16, Item 6-10)
  - Unframed tempera on paper titled Ultramarinblau, by Rolf Hanns, December 1985 (Box 16, Item 11)
  - 1 Box of 22 slides, chiefly of pages from Feldman's scores (Box 16, Item 12)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Composers--New York (State)--Buffalo
Genres
Correspondence; Clippings; Photographs; Interviews; Lectures
Associated Material
Separated Material
The following material was received with the collection but was either incorporated into the general collection of the Music Library or discarded.
Scores
Most music scores received with the collection were cataloged to the general collection of the Music Library.
Correspondence regarding the 1975-1976 June in Buffalo festivals
These folders transferred to the June in Buffalo Archive.
Books
A small number of music-related titles were added to the general collection of the Music Library; the remainder of the books were discarded. The discarded titles included Feldman's collection of books about carpets and catalogs of carpet exhibitions and auctions. The list of titles related to carpets and art is fairly extensive. Reflective as they are of Feldman's interests in these areas, the complete list is presented below.
Carpet books
Bennett, Ian. Book of Oriental Carpets and Rugs
Besim, Adil. Türkische Teppiche
Biggs, Robert D. Discoveries From Kurdish Looms
Brelant, Anthony and Mary Hunt Kahlenberg. Walk in Beauty: The Navajo and Their Blankets
Brüggemann, W. & H. Böhmer. Teppiche der Bauern und Nomaden in Anatolien
Bunardout, Raymond. Turkish Rugs
Denny, Walter B. & Robert Pinner, editors. Oriental Carpet & Textile Studies I
Dye, Daniel Sheets. Chinese Lattice Designs
Eiland, Murray L. Oriental Rugs: A Comprehensive Guide rev. and expanded ed.
Ellis, Charles Grant. Early Caucasian Rugs
Emery, Irene. The Primary Structures of Fabrics: An Illustrated Classification
Erdmann, Kurt. Seven Hundred Years of Oriental Carpets
Frauenknecht, Bertram and Klaus Frantz. Anatolische Gebetskelims
Gans-Ruedin, E. Iranian Carpets: Art, Craft and History
Haack, Hermann. Oriental Rugs: An Illustrated Guide
Hawley, Walter A. Oriental Rugs: Antique and Modern
Hegenbart, Heinz. Rare Oriental woven Bags
Housego, Jenny. Tribal Rugs: An Introduction to the Weaving of the Tribes of Iran
Kazakh and Uzbek Rugs from Afghanistan
Maritz, J. Turkish Carpets
James, George Wharton. Indian Blankets and Their Makers
Kendrick, A.F. & C.E.C. Tattersall. Hand-Woven Carpets: Oriental & European
Konieczny, M. G. Textiles of Baluchistan
Landreau, Anthony N. and W. R. Pickering. From the Bosporus to Samarkand Flat-Woven Rugs
Landreau, Anthony N., ed. Yörük: The Nomadic Weaving Tradition of the Middle East
Mackie, Louise W. and Jerome A. Straka, eds. The Oriental Rug Collection of Jerome and Mary Jane Straka
Mackie, Louise W. and Jon Thompson, eds. Turkmen: Tribal Carpets and Traditions
Milhofer, Stefan A. The Colour Treasury of Oriental Rugs
Mills, John. Carpets in Pictures
Petsopoulos, Yanni. Kilims: Flat-Woven Tapestry Rugs
Pickering, William Russell. Portraits of Joseph V. McMullan; includes "The Second Day of Ramadan" by Yohe, Ralph S.
Schümann, Ulrich. Oriental Carpets
Spuhler, Griedrich and Hans König and Martin Volkmann. Old Eastern Carpets: Masterpieces in German Private Collections
Thompson, Jon. Carpet Magic
Turkish Rugs: The Rachel B. Stevens Memorial Collection. Intro. by Joseph V. McMullan.
Walker, Daniel S. Oriental Rugs of the Hajji Baba
Willborg, Peter. David Block and Clive Loveless, eds. Flatweaves from Fjord and Forest: Scandinavian Tapestries of the 18th and 19th Centuries.
Yetkin, Serare. Historical Turkish Carpets
1985 Carpet Picture Calendar/Date Book
Carpet journals
HALI: the international journal of oriental carpets and textiles
½ (Summer 1978)
1/3 (Autumn 1978)
1/4 (Winter 1978)
2/1 (Spring 1979)
2/2 (Summer 1979)
2/3 (Autumn 1979)
2/4 (1980) - 6/3 issue 23 (1984)
7/1 issue 25 (1985) - 9/2 issue 34 (April/May/June 1987)
The Textile Museum Journal
21 (1982)
Carpet exhibit catalogs
Three of the catalogs are now shelved in Lockwood Library. Call numbers are indicated below.
Beattie, May H. Carpets of Central Persia with Special Reference to Rugs of Kirman. Catalogue of an exhibition held 10 April-19 May at the Mappin Art Gallery, Sheffield, and 4 June-11 July at the City Museum and Art Gallery, Birmingham.
Boucher, Jeff W. and H. McCoy Jones. The Ersari and Their Weavings. 1975 Christmas Exhibition of the International Hajji Baba Society